[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
trienes tasa automation tutorial as you
all know I already published 68 YouTube
videos covering beginners level
intermediate level and advanced level
concepts of automation by using BST TSA
from few videos onwards I have started
teaching you the realtime scenarios
where you might encounter different
types of obstacles and how can we
mitigate those obstacles while
automating the test cases please do
subscribe to the channel click on Bell
icon you'll receive notifications
whenever I publish more videos don't
forget to like and share the video thank
you
this is our lesson 69 in terms of
overall tricentis Taska training and
this is abstral 27 in terms of realtime
scenarios in this lesson I'm going to
teach you how can we solve an
obstacle where you need to interact with
an object like edit Box by using
steering parameter and the scrolling
Behavior techniques so now let us see in
detail what is the obstacle that we are
going to solve
for so this is the obstacle list that we
have started working on from few lessons
onwards so in today's lesson we going to
start working on scroll into view
obstacle which is categorized as medium
let's go for
it so here you can see the obstacle
enter toss
into the text box then submit text
appears once text box is out of visible
area so you can see here now it is not
very
straightforward text box to enter the
value what we need to do is so this edit
box is blocked by an i frame okay if I
scroll scroll down to the bottom now I
can access this edit box if I
enter the text as TSA in edit box and
submit it that means you solve the
automation problem
successfully so
basically you cannot enter the value
directly into this edit box so this edit
box is being blocked
by another object so to enter the
information into the edit box you need
to scroll down to see the text box and
then enter the text task so this is the
problem that we need to solve so now let
us jump onto the
prenta and start automating the test
case so as usual in module section we
are storing all the objects that are
required to solve the obstacles so here
we going to scan the objects that are
required to automate today's obstacle
what we need to do right click on this
obstacles folder select
scan
application so this is the application
that we would like to scan so I'm going
to click on scan
so here you can see I have a text
field where we'll be entering the tasa
as a text select this
one and also I have another object
called submit button which I need to
click on where I'll be
submitting the text that I have entered
so if You observe closely see this text
field is
under HTML document basically this is
under
iframe and then HTML document under HTML
document you have a text field that's
why this text field is actually blocking
by another object as well by an another
object okay so now let us
rename this module with the obstacle
name
copy and then rename this module
renaming the module is very important so
I'm renaming the module with the
obstacle name and now save the
module and then close your X scan so let
us go back to our trient tasa now if you
scroll down so this is the one that we
have scanned just now
obstacles double click on this so now
you can see there is a submit button and
there is a text field now let us create
a new test case so that we can automate
the test case come to the come to the
left side of the blue section which is
test case section right click on this
obstacles folder and then select create
test case and name this as with the same
obstacle
name now double click on this so to
automate the scenario that I have
explained you right you have to first
scroll down and then enter the text so
to perform scrolling operation we have
to do some modification to our object
properties what we are going to do come
to text field
for text field you have to open the
properties by clicking on by clicking on
this Arrow Mark okay open the properties
so what we need to do we need to
add a property to the text field
scrolling Behavior property what is that
property steering parameter property so
if you see here these are all the
properties of this text field now I
would like to add a steering parameter
what is that right click on this text
field and this is your steering
parameter create steering
parameter select this now you need to
now you need to rename this as scrolling
Behavior
scrolling
Behavior the spelling should be same you
should have capital S capital B and
there is no space scrolling behavior and
this scrolling Behavior we can provide
four different values one is top bottom
center or none okay in our case to get
our text box to the
focus our text box should be at the top
so that means your scrolling behavior of
this text field should be top so what
I'm going to do here I'm going to
specify it as
top scrolling Behavior top now save the
changes so now let us start automating
the test case so this is my test case to
automate the test case you need to drag
and drop the module onto the test
case
now first what we need to do we need to
enter the value to the text field so I'm
going to enter a value as
tasar as we already provided the
steering parameter as stop now you need
need not to perform any scrolling
operation okay so that is important and
now again I would like to drag this and
drop here onto the test
case and here I would like to click on
submit
button so let me so let me rename these
steps I'm going to rename this as enter
text and
this
click
submit right now save your test
case and let us Mark the test case as
completed now let's run the test case
and see how it works before that I would
like to just click on try again
so that application state will be ready
for execution ready for
execution now let's right click and run
the test case in
scratchbook see it entered the text you
can see here it scroll down as well as
it entered see here it performed the
scroll down how it is performing scroll
down by using the scrolling Behavior top
so the edit box moved to the top and
then it entered the text so this is how
you can solve an
obstacle which involves this scrolling
behavior and steering
parameters so if you have any queries
leave your queries in the comment box
I'll try to respond to your
queries hope you all understand how to
solve an obstacle where you need to
interact with an object by using the
techniques like steering parameter and
the scrolling Behavior
Concepts please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos don't forget to like and
share the video thank you
[Music]